Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2001
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Haupt, Irene
1 box (48 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 48 photographs of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2001 at the University at Buffalo.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2002.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
All images are available in the UB Libraries Digital Collections as part of the overall June in Buffalo Collection.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2001 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001 contains 48 images of participants in the festival for 2001. The list of musicians includes Pierre-Yves Artaud, Helena Bugallo, Amy Williams, Cassatt String Quartet, Dora Ohrenstein, Cort Lippe, Jeffrey Stadelman, David Felder, Magnus Martensson, and Jonathan Golove.
Arrangement
One sequence of images in alphabetical order by principal subject of the image.
Container List
- Photographs, June 2001, I.
  - Pierre-Yves Artaud, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 01)
  - Pierre-Yves Artaud and Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02)
  - Robert Berkman at pianola, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 03)
  - Kevin Bowyer at Slee organ, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 04)
  - Bugallo Williams Piano Duo, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05)
  - Bugallo Williams Piano Duo, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 06)
  - Bugallo Williams Piano Duo and John Gibson, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 07)
  - Cassatt String Quartet, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 08)
  - Kerry Grant and David Felder, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09)
  - David Felder, Magnus Martensson, and Pierre-Yves Artaud, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
  - David Felder, Cort Lippe, Jonathan Golove, and Jeff Stadelman, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Erik Ona, Cort Lippe, Jeff Stadelman, David Felder, and Jonathan Golove, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
  - David Felder, Alejandro Rutty, Jonathan Golove, and June in Buffalo students, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Mara Gibson, composer and June in Buffalo administrator, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Mara Gibson, Alejandro Rutty, Lorena Guillen, Eryk Anspach, Justin Kagan, Rin Ozaki, and Satoshi Takagi, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Jonathan Golove, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Kerry Grant, Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Emil Harnas, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Emil Harnas and Kevin Bowyer, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Hye-Jeong Lee, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Cort Lippe, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Cort Lippe, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Cort Lippe lecturing in Baird Recital Hall, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Magnus Martensson conducting, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Anthony Miranda, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Sam Mirelman, Elise LaVoie, and Clemens Merkel, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Sam Mirelman with Quatuor Bozzini, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Dora Ohrenstein, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Dora Ohrenstein with ensemble, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Erik Ona conducting brass and percussion ensemble, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Outer Circle Orchestra performing at UB Student Commons, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Pedro Rivadenera and Stephanie Bozzini, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Pedro Rivadenera and Isabelle Bozzini, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Jane Romano, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Jane Romano, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Alejandro Rutty conducting Lorena Guillen and ensemble, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Eric Rynes, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Eric Rynes, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Jeffrey Stadelman reading musical score, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Jeffrey Stadelman checking musical score, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Jeffrey Stadelman, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Jeffrey Stadelman, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Jeffrey Stadelman and Erik Ona, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Jeffrey Stadelman and Cassatt String Quartet, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 44)
  - Suzanne Thomas and Beth Ann Brenneman, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Cort Lippe, Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman, David Felder, Jeff Stadelman, Jonathan Golove, June 2001, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 48)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2000
Mus. Arc. 18
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2000 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002
Mus. Arc. 20
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2002 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2003 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2004 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2005 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2011 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.